The future ain't what it used to be.
The Croods: A New Age is a animation, family,
adventure film directed by Joel Crawford.
Searching for a safer habitat, the prehistoric Crood family discovers an
idyllic, walled-in paradise that meets all of its needs.
Unfortunately, they must also learn to live with the Bettermans -- a family
that's a couple of steps above the Croods on the evolutionary ladder.
As tensions between the new neighbors start to rise, a new threat soon propels both clans on an epic adventure
that forces them to embrace their differences, draw strength from one another, and survive together.
Grug (voice), played by Nicolas Cage.
Eep (voice), played by Emma Stone.
Guy (voice), played by Ryan Reynolds.
Ugga (voice), played by Catherine Keener.
Gran (voice), played by Cloris Leachman.
Thunk (voice), played by Clark Duke.
The Croods: A New Age (also known as The Croods 2) is a 2020 American
animated adventure comedy film produced by DreamWorks Animation.
It is the sequel to The Croods (2013), and was directed by Joel Crawford, and
written by Paul Fisher, Bob Logan, and Dan and Kevin Hageman.
Nicolas Cage, Emma Stone, Ryan Reynolds, Catherine Keener, Clark Duke, and Cloris Leachman reprise their roles
from the original film, with Leslie Mann, Peter Dinklage, and Kelly Marie Tran joining the cast.
The film follows the Croods, Guy, and their pets Belt, Chunky, and Douglas as they
discover an idyllic, walled-in paradise that meets all of their needs.
However, they must also learn to live with the Bettermans, a family a
couple of steps above the Croods on the evolutionary ladder.
The sequel was first announced in April 2013, with directors Chris
Sanders and Kirk DeMicco returning to helm the film.
Its development continued through 2014 and 2015 until its cancellation in November 2016 due to
doubts in response to NBCUniversal's August 2016 acquisition of DreamWorks Animation.
However, the project was revived in September 2017, with Crawford replacing Sanders and
DeMicco as directors in the following month, though they retain story credit.
Due to the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States, most of the
animating process was done from the crew's homes.
The Croods: A New Age was theatrically released in the United
States on November 25, 2020, by Universal Pictures.
It grossed $215 million against its $65 million budget and received mixed
reviews, with critics calling it "a decent-enough follow-up".
The film was nominated for the Golden Globe Award
for Best Animated Feature Film.
The film explores themes of sequel, prehistory,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger, candid.
The tone is lighthearted.